<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>stanfordirl.com</title>
   
   <link>https://stanfordirl.com/</link>
   <description>This is a chronicle of the lives of my former classmates and the amazing things they do after Stanford. Your daily dose of existential crisis. You're welcome. </description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Parimarjan Negi (B.S. ‘18)</title>
	  <link>//parimarjan-negi-bs18</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2018-12-31T02:18:00-08:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//parimarjan-negi-bs18</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>In certain circles, Negi can be considered a celebrity. During his first week on campus, the Stanford Daily excitedly ran the article: <a href="https://www.stanforddaily.com/2014/09/24/qa-with-a-freshmen-chess-grandmaster/">“Q&amp;A with the Class of 2018’s Chess Grandmaster”</a>. According to the Daily, he became a chess grandmaster at “13 years and four months, beating Magnus Carlsen’s record by a month to become the second-youngest grandmaster ever.”</p>

<p>My first memory of us was when we worked on a CS106A assignment together with Trisha. Procrastinating, Trisha told me about Negi’s chess fame. I stared at him in disbelief: “Then why does it take you so long to do this assignment?”</p>

<p>Over the years, we became good friends. He’s one of the most generous, unassuming people that I know – one of the few people I felt like I could be real with. I used to be jealous of the attention he got from our math professors. I was killing it in their classes but never got as much as an acknowledging nod from them, while Negi could just turn in his half-assed assignments and those profs would coyly smile at him and ask: “What do you think of the match last night?”</p>

<p>We lived together one summer with two other chess players during which time I was occasionally dumbfounded by his lack of greatness in non-chess areas. I once caught him trying to peel an avocado by first cutting it into a hundred of little triangles, then peeling each triangle one by one. “I thought avocados were supposed to be easy,” he whined.</p>

<p>For a while, I wasn’t sure what Negi was up to. He has this slow, unexcited way of talking that makes it seem like he’s not interested in anything. It’s also not helpful that he sometimes just shut down his phone and locked himself in his stuffy little room. He subsisted on junk food and soylent. He gained weight.</p>

<p>Then I ran into him at NIPS 2017 where he was presenting his paper at a workshop. He had picked up research and apparently did well in it. He developed a penchant for this elusive (and gross) field of computer science called “system”. “You look like somebody who would be interested in system,” I told him. He chuckled.</p>

<p>I don’t know how he managed to do it but he got into CS PhD programs at both Stanford and MIT. He chose MIT for the professor and the sad weather that gives him excuse to stay indoor all the time. He came back to the Bay Area over the break for a chess tournament. “The strongest open tournament”, one of the organizers took pain to make sure that this fact is known. “Negi is only the fourth strongest player.”</p>

<p>He didn’t do well in the tournament, which got him down a little. “Chess sucks,” he complained [there, that’s the answer for the person who asked on Quora why Parimarjan Negi stopped playing professional chess]. But overall, MIT seems to agree with Negi. He’s working on bringing Artificial Intelligence into computer system, using algorithms to allocate system depending on the upcoming requirements for each application under professor (Mohammad Alizadeh)[https://people.csail.mit.edu/alizadeh/]. “A fourth year PhD at my lab uses a neural network to decide bit-rates for future video chunks based on observations collected by client video players. It’s implemented at Facebook. My research will be a generalized version of that.”</p>

<p>He’s happy and social again. We had lunch, tried something, roamed around SF during the new year’s eve, and laughed at everything until our ribs hurt. He’s been working out and on diet. He lost 80 pounds within a year. At some point, he had discernible six-pack abs but now “it’s bulking season.” He even started dating.</p>

<p>“That’s amazing, man. How did you do it?”<br />
“No carb and weight lifting.”<br />
“You should write about it.”<br />
“Uh this guy already wrote about it. I just did exactly what he did.”</p>

<p>I rolled my eyes. He’s still as self-effacing as ever.</p>

<h2 id="books-that-negi-is-reading">Books that Negi is reading:</h2>

<h2 id="three-people-negi-would-like-to-be-featured-next-on-stanfordirl">Three people Negi would like to be featured next on StanfordIRL:</h2>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Zack Lawrence (B.S. ‘18 - dropout)</title>
	  <link>//zack-lawrence-bs18</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2018-09-14T03:18:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//zack-lawrence-bs18</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>A few weeks ago, I went for a run with Michael (B.S. ‘18), who was working on his crypto trading platform. He mentioned other people in our class who were also working on crypto.</p>

<p>“Do you know Zack Lawrence? His company has been hiring so many people from Stanford.”<br />
“Wait, is he back?”<br />
“Oh yes. His office is in SF.”</p>

<p>Zack and I used to hang out in college. We met through Dan Boneh’s cryptography class – he visited a mutual friend in my dorm and ended up helping me with my homework. We then were in game theory class together and became good friends. Soon after that, he dropped out of school to start a company with his roommate/best friend <a href="https://stanfordirl.com//tag/axel-ericsson">Axel Ericsson</a> (B.S. ‘18). They moved to Berlin, then London. Like most long distance friendships, ours gradually fizzled out. I suspect it might also have something to do with his having a lot of cryptocurrencies and my lack of them.</p>

<p>I hadn’t seen Zack for 2 years, and I was excited to see how he was doing. He didn’t respond to me for a week. “Sorry, I was with a company retreat in the Philippines.” We kept planning but all our plannings fell through until this evening, Zack asked me what I was up to.</p>

<p>“My roommate and I just went to Safeway and got a party size bag of M&amp;Ms,” said I.<br />
“Want to hang out in SF?”<br />
“Google Maps says the train can take me to SF by 11pm so guess not.”<br />
“How about Uber?”<br />
“Do I look like a crypto millionaire to you?”<br />
“Lemme call you a Uber.”</p>

<p>Zack is sharing an apartment on the 34th floor overlooking the Bay with Axel and a British guy he works with. His startup is currently named Vest, rebranded from 1protocol. Two things I never understand about crypto companies:
They love having numbers in their names (1conformation, ob1, 1xbit, etc.)
Everyone has a whitepaper.</p>

<p>Their company allows people to do staking on Ethereum. He tried to explain what it meant to me but when facing with complex information on a Friday evening, my dense head has the tendency to zone out. You can read more about his startup <a href="https://medium.com/vest/introducing-1protocol-d2f239285386">here</a>. Yes, there’s a link to their whitepaper in that post.</p>

<p>In general, I’m happy to report that even though Zack is as flaky as he was in college and as stressed as any startup founder, he’s doing well. His startup is backed by prestigious investors. He reads good books and enjoys good food. He has a good group of friends and he seems to be a good manager.</p>

<p>“I heard you’ve hired a lot of people from Stanford,” said I.<br />
“Yeah, we have about xx people now and more than half are from Stanford our year.”<br />
“Isn’t it weird to hire your friends?”<br />
“Why?”<br />
“You might be an asshole to them now that they work under you.”<br />
“I can be an asshole to them even if they don’t work for me.”<br />
“True that.”</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Viraj Mehta (B.S. ‘18, M.S. '18)</title>
	  <link>//viraj-mehta-bs18</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2018-07-21T03:18:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//viraj-mehta-bs18</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Viraj texted me today. He had got into the robotics PhD program at CMU but deferred it for one year to work on a crypto fund with Gabe (<a href="https://stanfordirl.com//tag/gabriel-bianconi/">Gabriel Bianconi</a>, <a href="https://stanfordirl.com//tag/b.s.-17/">B.S. ‘17</a>). “It’s not working out and I don’t know what to do.”</p>

<p>He sounded a bit nervous so we facetimed. He was in Texas with his parents. We went over his options – I tried to suggest a few things but they were all in Bay Area and Viraj was determined to be in New York. I honestly didn’t know why he was nervous. Viraj is extremely intense and has been dubbed by my friend Paul Warren (B.S ‘17) as one of the smartest people he knows. He’s interned at Cisco, Visa, and Google. In our senior year, he went on college Jeopardy! and finished third-place with a check for $25,000, flipping off the entire nation in the process. See <a href="https://learn365project.com/2017/02/23/day-290-did-viraj-mehta-really-flip-of-american-people/">his famed middle finger</a>.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
