<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>stanfordirl.com</title>
   
   <link>https://stanfordirl.com/</link>
   <description>This is a chronicle of the lives of my former classmates and the amazing things they do after Stanford. Your daily dose of existential crisis. You're welcome. </description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Lucio Dery (B.S. ‘17, M.S. ‘18)</title>
	  <link>//lucio-dery-bs17</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2018-10-08T03:18:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//lucio-dery-bs17</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Lucio likes telling the story when we first met. He was complaining (more like humble-bragging) about the pressure he felt because so many kids in Ghana looked up to him and I shot him down like fireworks.</p>

<p>“There are 2000 people following me on Facebook,” he said.<br />
“I have 80,000,” I said.</p>

<p>We worked together on an automatic essay grading project that he carried me through. Lucio majored in Physics (brain alert) but had an amazing grasp of math and programming. By the end of his coterm, he had an offer to join Facebook AI Research (FAIR) in Paris - a position that he really wanted.</p>

<p>So I was surprised when he texted me he was in Bay Area. Instead of joining FAIR in Paris, he joined the new FAIR office in Seattle.</p>

<p>“Why would anyone choose Seattle over Paris?”<br />
“I was going through a lot of personal stuff and didn’t want to deal with it in a new country. Yeah, don’t worry, I’m fine now.”</p>

<p>Indeed he looked fine. He had finally decided to embrace his hipsterness and proudly wore his gray, big-lense hipster glasses. He also works out everyday. Even though he’s still trying to navigate his new job (it took him a long time to settle on what project to work on – which is language modeling on Wikipedia), he enjoys living in Seattle.</p>

<p><img alt="Lucio Dery" src="https://stanfordirl.com//assets/images/people/lucio-dery.jpg" style="float: center; max-width: 80%; margin: 0 0 1em 2em" /></p>

<p>Reasons why he loves Seattle:</p>

<ul>
  <li>A girl hit on him for the first time ever. “That would never happen in Bay Area,” said Lucio.</li>
  <li>It’s good to get out of the Stanford bubble (but he still lives with a bunch of friends from college).</li>
  <li>Housing is so cheap. They have an actual guest room.</li>
  <li>Tax is so low. [Lucio: “I don’t even know what to do with all the money I have now.” Me: “Have you heard of something called cryptocurrency?”]</li>
</ul>

<p>Despite his love for Seattle, he still visits Bay Area every month for work. Next September, he will be starting his Ph.D. at CMU. He’s progressively moving to areas with worse weather. Wish him luck.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Viraj Mehta (B.S. ‘18, M.S. '18)</title>
	  <link>//viraj-mehta-bs18</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2018-07-21T03:18:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//viraj-mehta-bs18</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Viraj texted me today. He had got into the robotics PhD program at CMU but deferred it for one year to work on a crypto fund with Gabe (<a href="https://stanfordirl.com//tag/gabriel-bianconi/">Gabriel Bianconi</a>, <a href="https://stanfordirl.com//tag/b.s.-17/">B.S. ‘17</a>). “It’s not working out and I don’t know what to do.”</p>

<p>He sounded a bit nervous so we facetimed. He was in Texas with his parents. We went over his options – I tried to suggest a few things but they were all in Bay Area and Viraj was determined to be in New York. I honestly didn’t know why he was nervous. Viraj is extremely intense and has been dubbed by my friend Paul Warren (B.S ‘17) as one of the smartest people he knows. He’s interned at Cisco, Visa, and Google. In our senior year, he went on college Jeopardy! and finished third-place with a check for $25,000, flipping off the entire nation in the process. See <a href="https://learn365project.com/2017/02/23/day-290-did-viraj-mehta-really-flip-of-american-people/">his famed middle finger</a>.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
