<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>stanfordirl.com</title>
   
   <link>https://stanfordirl.com/</link>
   <description>This is a chronicle of the lives of my former classmates and the amazing things they do after Stanford. Your daily dose of existential crisis. You're welcome. </description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Akash Modi (B.S. ‘17, M.S. ‘19)</title>
	  <link>//akash-modi-bs17</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2018-11-24T02:18:00-08:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//akash-modi-bs17</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Since I was feeling weird – every once in a while I felt the urge to be extremely anti-social and flake out of all social functions, including the Friendsgiving dinner hosted at his place the night before – Akash came to visit me. When I offered him a beer, he said: “I don’t drink that much. I’m a professional athlete, remember?”</p>

<p>So we made ginger tea and sat outside under our Christmas light. I realized that while Akash and I were in the same friend group and had lunch together almost every day for half a year, it was the first time we had ever talked one-on-one. I guess that’s the beauty of graduation. You no longer hang out with people just because everyone is hanging out, but because you want to get to know someone.</p>

<p>While I’d been sitting on my ass whining, Akash just came back from a month traveling: 2 weeks in Doha for the world championship, 1 week in Stuttgart for a German professional gymnastics league.</p>

<p>“But you aren’t German?”<br />
“Each team is allowed to have 2 foreigners compete for them, so the Heilbronn team asked me to join.”<br />
“So you are a gymnastic mercenary.”<br />
“Yeah.”<br />
“Did the travel affect your classes?”<br />
“Oh, I’m taking a quarter off.”<br /></p>

<p>Akash was doing what we called “slow-terming”: finishing the coterm (bachelor’s + master’s) in 6 years instead of 5. He has only 8 classes left but chose to spread them over a year.</p>

<p>“If I didn’t have gymnastics, I might have tried to do it in 4 years. But I’m practicing about 30 hours a week with a lot of travels.”<br />
“I rushed through college and I saw no point in doing so. I don’t see how you managed your coursework while being a full time athlete.”<br />
“Just trying to enjoy it, you know.”<br />
“At what age do gymnasts usually retire?”<br />
“For men, it’s around 26. So I have a few more years.”<br />
“What’s your plan after that?”<br />
“Getting a job,” laughed Akash. “I’m a bit worried since I have been so busy with gymnastics I haven’t done any internship.”<br />
“I’m sure companies understand. If I had a resume from a candidate who was an Olympian I’d bend over backwards to interview that candidate. You also have a bachelor’s and master’s degree in mechanical engineering from Stanford.”<br />
“I hope so. But I’m not an Olympian yet.”<br /></p>

<p>Akash’s goal for this year is to make it to the Olympics 2020. He was an alternate at Rio 2016. He was part of the USA gymnastics team but didn’t compete. He was there as a replacement in case something bad happened to somebody in the main team. Somebody said it was the best deal — you got to travel and stay in nice hotels and meet athletic people without the actual pressure of competing. But Akash told me that it was the worse feeling. He trained his whole life for that moment, and he got so close.</p>

<p>Go Akash! If you make it to the Olympics this year, I’ll buy you the biggest Taco Bell’s meal you’ve ever had in your life. Side note: Akash loves Taco Bell. He once said on national television that he got to compete in the world championship because he ate Taco Bell every day.</p>

<h2 id="books-that-john-is-reading">Books that John is reading:</h2>

<h2 id="three-people-john-would-like-to-be-featured-next-on-stanfordirl">Three people John would like to be featured next on StanfordIRL:</h2>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>John Luttig (B.S. ‘17)</title>
	  <link>//john-luttig-bs17</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2018-11-02T05:18:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//john-luttig-bs17</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Having an hour between meetings in SF, I was trying to think of what to do when I thought of John Luttig, an associate at Founders Fund. John and I knew each from section leading but weren’t close. I remembered seeing his face on a door poster when he was running for the student senate and thought: “I’d never be as ‘out there’ as this guy.” Over the years, I occasionally hit him up for advice and he was always accommodating. When I messaged him to meet up, he gave me a list of neighborhoods he’d be in depending on the time of the day.</p>

<p>“Oh and disclaimer we’re not hiring,” added John at the end of his message.</p>

<p>We met at 5pm at a coffee shop and John was fresh out of his shower. It wasn’t that he ended his workday early. It’s just that there isn’t a clear work/life separation for VCs: he hangs out with people he hopes to bring him deals one day and his friends are sometimes in his portfolio.</p>

<p>“How would you describe your friend circle?” asked I.<br />
“Some are from the fund, some are founders, my girlfriend, some from the Thiel Fellowship.”<br />
“Not many people from Stanford?”<br />
“Some. Part of my job is to keep tab on Stanford grads, particularly those considering starting companies or looking for a new interesting gig.”<br />
“How do you define an ‘interesting gig?”<br />
“Any job that you can’t apply for.”<br /></p>

<p>I asked him about the PS he added at the end of his message.</p>

<p>“Are there a lot of Stanford people asking you for jobs?”<br />
“A decent amount. I’m sorry, did I offend you? I just thought I should be upfront.”<br />
“Not at all. I found it funny. Nobody has given me that disclaimer before. Most people did the opposite thing. They wanted to hang out then tried to recruit me.”<br />
“You wouldn’t like being a VC anyway.” [I rolled my eyes. VCs always say that.]</p>

<p>“Do you live up to the VC stereotype?”<br />
“Well, I do own a pair of Allbirds but I try not to wear them that much. I definitely don’t wear those VC vests. I think some people don’t like VCs because they think we’re transactional. It’s our job to constantly evaluate potential deals. But I try not to do that when I’m with my friends.”<br />
“Do you work with Peter Thiel often?”<br />
“Founders Fund’s office is small so I see him around.”<br />
“He’s a controversial figure.”<br />
“I think he’s incredibly thoughtful and helpful. He is the reason I’m where I am today.”<br />
“How so?”<br />
“I was the editor in chief of the Stanford Review. It was founded by Peter Thiel. That’s how I got to know him. I interned with the Thiel Fellowship before.”<br />
“Are you happy with where you are?”<br />
“Yes. I’ve been incredibly lucky.”<br /></p>

<p><img alt="John Luttig" src="https://stanfordirl.com//assets/images/people/john-luttig.jpg" style="float: center; max-width: 50%; margin: 0 0 1em 0.5em" /></p>

<p>I walked him back to his place, a fancy-looking apartment in Pac Heights. He was about to pick up his girlfriend since college, <a href="https://stanfordirl.com/tag/melisa-tokmak/">Melisa Tokmak (B.S. ‘17)</a>, who is a product manager at Facebook. He’s happy with his work and with his relationship. He runs a <a href="https://us19.campaign-archive.com/home/?u=08307b0615c07686e2049c8ea&amp;id=2b5966acb1">weekly newsletter</a> in which he shares one thing he’s learned and one question he’s thinking about. He also hosts poker nights every Tuesday. Don’t shoot him an email if you want a job, but shoot him an email if you want to brainstorm about your career or company.</p>

<p>Books that John is reading:</p>
<ul>
  <li>A Military History of the Western World (From the Defeat of the Spanish Armada to the Battle of Waterloo) (reading Volume II rn (finished vol I))</li>
  <li>Hegel’s Phenomenology of Spirit</li>
</ul>

<p>Three people John would like to be featured next on StanfordIRL:</p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://stanfordirl.com/tag/chris-sauer/">Chris Sauer</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://stanfordirl.com/tag/akshay-rampuria/">Akshay Rampuria</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://stanfordirl.com/tag/grant-sanderson/">Grant Sanderson</a></li>
</ul>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Lucio Dery (B.S. ‘17, M.S. ‘18)</title>
	  <link>//lucio-dery-bs17</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2018-10-08T03:18:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//lucio-dery-bs17</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Lucio likes telling the story when we first met. He was complaining (more like humble-bragging) about the pressure he felt because so many kids in Ghana looked up to him and I shot him down like fireworks.</p>

<p>“There are 2000 people following me on Facebook,” he said.<br />
“I have 80,000,” I said.</p>

<p>We worked together on an automatic essay grading project that he carried me through. Lucio majored in Physics (brain alert) but had an amazing grasp of math and programming. By the end of his coterm, he had an offer to join Facebook AI Research (FAIR) in Paris - a position that he really wanted.</p>

<p>So I was surprised when he texted me he was in Bay Area. Instead of joining FAIR in Paris, he joined the new FAIR office in Seattle.</p>

<p>“Why would anyone choose Seattle over Paris?”<br />
“I was going through a lot of personal stuff and didn’t want to deal with it in a new country. Yeah, don’t worry, I’m fine now.”</p>

<p>Indeed he looked fine. He had finally decided to embrace his hipsterness and proudly wore his gray, big-lense hipster glasses. He also works out everyday. Even though he’s still trying to navigate his new job (it took him a long time to settle on what project to work on – which is language modeling on Wikipedia), he enjoys living in Seattle.</p>

<p><img alt="Lucio Dery" src="https://stanfordirl.com//assets/images/people/lucio-dery.jpg" style="float: center; max-width: 80%; margin: 0 0 1em 2em" /></p>

<p>Reasons why he loves Seattle:</p>

<ul>
  <li>A girl hit on him for the first time ever. “That would never happen in Bay Area,” said Lucio.</li>
  <li>It’s good to get out of the Stanford bubble (but he still lives with a bunch of friends from college).</li>
  <li>Housing is so cheap. They have an actual guest room.</li>
  <li>Tax is so low. [Lucio: “I don’t even know what to do with all the money I have now.” Me: “Have you heard of something called cryptocurrency?”]</li>
</ul>

<p>Despite his love for Seattle, he still visits Bay Area every month for work. Next September, he will be starting his Ph.D. at CMU. He’s progressively moving to areas with worse weather. Wish him luck.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
